const quizQuestions3en = 
[{
    question:"It is correct to say that in a fusion welding process:",
    answers: ["there is always the fusion of the base metal;",
    "a filler metal must always be added;",
    "heating of the joint region is not always necessary;",
    "there is no need to melt the base material, as long as there is the fusion of a filler metal."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"\"What does the term \"\"electrical conductivity\"\" mean?\"",
    answers: ["The ability to conduct electrical current.",
    "The ability to conduct electrical voltage.",
    "The ability to conduct electrical energy.",
    "The ability to resist to conducting electrical current."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What coated electrodes should be used to obtain better mechanical properties?",
    answers: ["rutile type electrodes (e.g., E6013).",
    "basic type electrodes (e.g., E7018).",
    "acid type electrodes (e.g., E7020).",
    "cellulosic type electrodes (e.g., E6010)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What coated electrodes should be used to obtain better weld appearance?",
    answers: ["rutile type electrodes (e.g., E6013).",
    "basic type electrodes (e.g., E7018).",
    "acid type electrodes (e.g., E7020).",
    "cellulosic type electrodes (e.g., E6010)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What coated electrodes should be used to obtain higher penetration?",
    answers: ["rutile type electrodes (e.g., E6013).",
    "basic type electrodes (e.g., E7018).",
    "acid type electrodes (e.g., E7020).",
    "cellulosic type electrodes (e.g., E6010)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following types of coated electrodes is most suitable for welding high-strength steels?",
    answers: ["rutile type electrodes (e.g., E6013).",
    "basic type electrodes (e.g., E7018).",
    "acid type electrodes (e.g., E7020).",
    "cellulosic type electrodes (e.g., E6010)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The speed of oxy-cutting depends on:",
    answers: ["the plate thickness, regardless cutting nozzle size;",
    "the cutting nozzle size only;",
    "the thickness of the plate only;",
    "the thickness of the plate, provided that the cutting nozzle used is adequate for the thickness to be cut."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say, when using oxy-cutting or plasma cutting, that ...",
    answers: ["the thicker the plate, the lower is the cutting speed;",
    "the thicker the plate, the higher is the cutting speed;",
    "the plasma cutting is suited better for larger thicknesses;",
    "the cutting speed is always the same, because for higher thicknesses, larger cutting nozzles are used with higher oxygen flow rates."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Shielding gases for GMAW (MIG/MAG welding) are primarily used to:",
    answers: ["supply alloying elements to the weld pool;",
    "ensure a proper metal transfer mode;",
    "prevent an atmospheric contamination of the weld pool;",
    "cool the welding torch."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An electric welding arc consists of:",
    answers: ["the anodic zone, the cathodic zone, the arc column and the arc-weld pool coupling;",
    "the anodic zone, the cathodic zone, the arc column and the arc-electrode coupling;",
    "the anodic zone, the cathodic zone, the arc column and the cathodic spots.",
    "the anodic zone, the cathodic zone and the arc column."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"If the arc length is shortened during welding, the arc voltage will:",
    answers: ["increase;",
    "decrease;",
    "stay always the same;",
    "stay the same in MIG/MAG welding (GMAW)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"If the arc is lengthened during welding, the arc voltage will:",
    answers: ["increase;",
    "decrease;",
    "stay always the same;",
    "stay the same in MIG/MAG welding (GMAW)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"If the arc length is shortened during welding, the current will:",
    answers: ["increase for SMAW and GMAW;",
    "decrease for SMAW and GMAW;",
    "stay always the same;",
    "stay the same in MIG/MAG welding (GMAW)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"If the arc is lengthened during welding, the current will:",
    answers: ["increase for SMAW and GMAW;",
    "decrease for SMAW and GMAW;",
    "stay always the same;",
    "stay the same in MIG/MAG welding (GMAW)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Constant Voltage (CV) arc welding power sources produce a:",
    answers: ["relatively flat volt-ampere curve;",
    "rising volt-amp curve;",
    "drooping volt-ampere curve;",
    "relatively vertical volt-ampere curve."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The power source of which output static characteristic would you use for welding with a coated electrode?",
    answers: ["That of Constant Voltage type.",
    "That of Constant Current type.",
    "That of Variable Voltage type.",
    "That of Variable Current type."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Shielding gases for GMAW (MIG/MAG welding) are primarily used to:",
    answers: ["stabilize the arc;",
    "ensure a proper metal transfer mode;",
    "eliminate atmospheric contamination of the weld pool;",
    "cool the welding torch."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In GTAW (TIG welding) the pure argon is primarily used to:",
    answers: ["stabilize the arc;",
    "avoid oxidation of the tungsten electrode;",
    "eliminate atmospheric contamination of the weld pool;",
    "cool the welding torch."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A long arc when using the GTAW (TIG welding) will produce:",
    answers: ["a narrow weld pool and deep penetration;",
    "a wide weld pool and deep penetration;",
    "a narrow weld pool and shallow penetration;",
    "a wide weld pool and shallow penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Heat is:",
    answers: ["a measure of the amount of energy;",
    "a measure of the amount of power;",
    "a measure of the temperature;",
    "a measure of the amount of potential energy of atoms."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of the Submerged Arc Welding (SAW)?",
    answers: ["The welded metal will be cooled at high rates, since it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "Only carbon steel can be welded.",
    "This process is not portable.",
    "It is not suitable for extreme conditions."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of the Submerged Arc Welding (SAW)?",
    answers: ["Only direct current with positive electrode polarity (DCEP) can be used.",
    "A high volume of fumes is produced in comparison to other arc welding processes.",
    "Only welding in the flat or horizontal position is feasible.",
    "It cannot be used for surfacing because of deep penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the electrical resistance of a metallic conductor, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The greater the resistivity of a conductor, the greater its resistance (for the same dimensions);",
    "The greater the length and diameter of a conductor, the greater its resistance;",
    "Resistivity is temperature dependent (for metals, the higher the temperature, the lower the electrical resistivity);",
    "The electrical resistance of a conductor depends on the shape of the cross section of the conductor. Conductors with a circular section are characterized by a lower resistance compared to conductors with triangular or square sections."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the electrical resistance of a metallic conductor, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The greater the length and diameter of a conductor, the greater its resistance;",
    "Resistivity is temperature dependent (for metals, the higher the temperature, the greater the electrical resistivity).",
    "Resistivity is temperature dependent (for metals, the higher the temperature, the lower the electrical resistivity);",
    "The electrical resistance of a conductor depends on the shape of the cross section of the conductor. Conductors with a circular section are characterized by a lower resistance compared to conductors with triangular or square sections."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the electrical resistance of a metallic conductor, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The greater the length and diameter of a conductor, the greater its resistance;",
    "Resistivity is temperature dependent (for metals, the higher the temperature, the lower the electrical resistivity);",
    "In conductors called non-ohmic, the relationship between the intensity of electric current and the voltage drop does not obey any specific relationship and its graphical representation can be any type of curve, except a straight line.",
    "The electrical resistance of a conductor depends on the shape of the cross section of the conductor. Conductors with a circular section are characterized by a lower resistance compared to conductors with triangular or square sections."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Joule Effect, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The Joule Effect is a phenomenon of heat generation in a metallic conductor when an electric current passes through it.",
    "The larger the cross section of the conductor, the greater the heat generation, with the same current;",
    "The heat generated in an electrical conductor when conducting high electrical current (as in the case of welding) practically does not depend on its electrical resistance;",
    "The heat generated in welding cables does not mean energy losses, as it is the natural effect that always accompanies the electric current."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"From these power sources, select the one recommended for GMAW (MIG/MAG welding):",
    answers: ["DC Constant Current.",
    "DC Constant Voltage.",
    "DC Electrode Negative Polarity.",
    "AC Constant Voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"From these power sources, select the one recommended for SMAW (MMA welding):",
    answers: ["DC Constant Current.",
    "DC Constant Voltage.",
    "AC Electrode Negative Polarity.",
    "AC Constant Voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"From these power sources, select the one recommended for GTAW (TIG welding):",
    answers: ["DC Constant Current.",
    "DC Constant Voltage.",
    "DC Electrode Negative Polarity.",
    "AC Constant Voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the operating principles of an electric transformer, it is correct to state that if the primary voltage is 220 V, the secondary voltage is 44 V and the output current is 100 A, the current consumed by the transformer from the public network will be (without taking into account losses):",
    answers: ["40 A.",
    "20 A.",
    "5.0 A.",
    "4.0 A."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the operating principles of an electric transformer, it is correct to state that if the primary voltage is 220 V, the secondary voltage is 55 V and the output current is 100 A, the current consumed by the transformer from the public network will be (without taking into account losses):",
    answers: ["40 A.",
    "25 A.",
    "20 A.",
    "4.0 A."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the operating principles of an electric transformer, it is correct to state that if the primary voltage is 220 V, the secondary voltage is 44 V and the current consumed by the transformer from the public network is 20 A, the output current will be (without take into account losses):",
    answers: ["200 A.",
    "100 A.",
    "50 A.",
    "40 A."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the operating principles of an electric transformer, it is correct to state that if the primary voltage is 220 V, the secondary voltage is 55 V and the current consumed by the transformer from the public network is 20 A, the output current will be (without take into account losses):",
    answers: ["100 A.",
    "80 A.",
    "50 A.",
    "40 A."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The number of windings on the primary side of a single-phase transformer is 500 and on the secondary side it is 100. The voltage on the primary side is 200 V and the secondary current is 10 A. So:",
    answers: ["The secondary side voltage is 1000 V.",
    "The secondary side voltage is 40 V.",
    "The current in the primary is 5 A.",
    "The current in the primary is 50 A."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The number of windings on the primary side of a single-phase transformer is 500 and on the secondary side it is 100. The voltage on the primary side is 200 V and the secondary current is 10 A. So:",
    answers: ["The secondary side voltage is 1000 V.",
    "The current in the primary is 5 A.",
    "The current in the primary is 2 A.",
    "The current in the primary is 50 A."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The number of windings on the primary side of a single-phase transformer is 400 and on the secondary side it is 100. The voltage on the primary side is 220 V and the secondary current is 100 A. So:",
    answers: ["The secondary side voltage is 55 V.",
    "The secondary side voltage is 25 V.",
    "The current in the primary is 2 A.",
    "The current in the primary is 10 A."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The number of windings on the primary side of a single-phase transformer is 400 and on the secondary side it is 100. The voltage on the primary side is 220 V and the secondary current is 100 A. So:",
    answers: ["The secondary side voltage is 110 V.",
    "The secondary side voltage is 25 V.",
    "The current in the primary is 2 A.",
    "The current in the primary is 25 A."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is meant by the output volt-ampere characteristic of a power source?",
    answers: ["The relationship between the primary (input) current and the secondary (output) voltage of the power source.",
    "The relationship between the voltage at the power source terminals and the current in the external circuit when the load (resistance) is slowly changed.",
    "The relationship between the voltage at the power source terminals and the current in the external circuit when the load (resistance) is rapidly changed.",
    "The variation of the secondary voltage and current at the power source terminals with time."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which arc welding process has the highest thermal efficiency (the most effective use of the heat energy generated by the arc)?",
    answers: ["GTAW/TIG welding (CCEN - negative electrode polarity).",
    "GTAW/TIG welding (CCEN - positive electrode polarity).",
    "Plasma arc welding (PAW).",
    "Submerged arc welding (SAW)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The no-load (open-circuit) voltage of a power source is:",
    answers: ["The voltage measured at the primary circuit terminals of the power source when welding is not performed.",
    "The voltage measured at the power source secondary circuit terminals during welding.",
    "The voltage measured at the power source secondary circuit terminals when it is turned on but welding is not performed.",
    "The voltage measured at the power supply secondary circuit terminals when the welder holds a prolonged short circuit."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Very limited types of material that can be welded.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "The equipment is more complex, more expensive and less portable compared to the SMAW (MMA welding) process.",
    "It requires a higher level of skill and dexterity when compared to the GTAW (TIG welding) process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Being a very slow process, it produces a large heat affected zone (HAZ) in the base material.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "Displays an open arc. Proper care must be taken to protect the welder and bystanders from harmful UV rays.",
    "It is not economically suitable to weld metals more than 6 mm thick."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Very limited types of material that can be welded.",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "It has higher maintenance costs compared to the SMAW (MMA welding) process.",
    "It requires a higher level of skill and dexterity when compared to the GTAW (TIG welding) process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["No need for good hand-eye coordination skills.",
    "No slag to obscure the welder's view of the molten pool.",
    "It is very suitable in extreme conditions (e.g., winds).",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current level, this process represents no risk of lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will cool at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "Higher welding speeds than many other welding processes.",
    "Lower UV radiation than many other welding processes.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Due to the possibility to weld at any current level, this process represents no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "Higher filler metal deposition rate than many other welding processes.",
    "Welded metal will cool at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "It is very suitable in extreme conditions (e.g., winds)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher UV radiation than many other welding processes.",
    "Not suitable in extreme conditions (e.g., winds).",
    "Deposition rates are typically lower than for GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "It requires a higher level of skill and dexterity when compared to the GTAW (TIG welding) process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "The metallurgical action is less pronounced compared to the GMAW (MIG/MAG welding) process.",
    "It is a manual welding process.",
    "Higher UV radiation than GTAW (TIG welding) and GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Deposition rates are lower than manual GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "The offer of covered electrodes on the market is limited.",
    "Expenses for consumables can be high due to a low efficiency of electrode use, around 65% only.",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding), this welding process is difficult to master."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher UV radiation than GTAW (TIG welding) and GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "Not suitable in extreme conditions (e.g., winds).",
    "It's difficult to be mechanized.",
    "It requires a higher level of skill and dexterity when compared to the GTAW (TIG welding) process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding), this welding process is difficult to master.",
    "The operating factor is typically low due to the need to change the stub to a new electrode and the need to remove slag.",
    "Deposition rates are lower than manual GTAW (TIG welding)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Deposition rates are lower than manual GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "The offer of covered electrodes on the market is limited.",
    "Slag must be removed unlike in GTAW (TIG welding) and GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "Higher UV radiation than GTAW (TIG welding) and GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Very limited types of material that can be welded.",
    "Deposition rates are lower than manual GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "More fumes are produced compared to GTAW (TIG welding) and GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "The offer of covered electrodes on the market is limited."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Very limited types of material that can be welded.",
    "Deposition rates are lower than manual GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "The process is discontinuous due to the limited length of the electrodes.",
    "It requires a higher level of skill and dexterity when compared to the GTAW (TIG welding) process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Higher UV radiation than GTAW (TIG welding) and GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "Basic type covered electrodes need to be dried to avoid internal porosity or poor operating characteristics.",
    "Unlike GTAW (TIG welding), this welding process is difficult to master."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Not suitable in extreme conditions (e.g., winds).",
    "Deposition rates are lower than manual GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "The operating characteristics of electrode of the same type can differ considerably from one manufacturer to another, therefore, the welder must always get used to a new electrode.",
    "The offer of covered electrodes on the market is limited."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Less fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "This process allows to weld thin materials and up to unlimited thickness using multiple passes.",
    "Unlike GMAW (MIG/MAG welding), this welding process is easier to master.",
    "It's easy to be mechanized."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Less fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "The process is very suitable for welding in confined spaces and in various positions with few problems.",
    "No need for good hand-eye coordination skills.",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current level, this process represents no risk of lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Due to the possibility to weld at any current level, this process represents no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "Most portable of all arc welding processes.",
    "Welded metal will cool at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "Unlike GMAW (MIG/MAG welding), this welding process is easier to master."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Unlike GMAW (MIG/MAG welding), this welding process is easier to master.",
    "Low-cost consumables.",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current level, this process represents no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "Welded metal will cool at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Less fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "It can be used in a wide variety of environments, including in the field, in workshops, to weld pipelines, on ships, bridges, ...",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current level, this process represents no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "Unlike GMAW (MIG/MAG welding), this welding process is easier to master."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Less fumes are produced compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "It is less sensitive to wind and air draft than GTAW (TIG welding) and GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "Welded metal will cool at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["It's easy to be mechanized.",
    "The equipment is relatively simple and portable and its cost is relatively low.",
    "This process is not sensitive to surface contaminants (such as rust, scale, dirt, oil and paint).",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current level, this process represents no risk of lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["Unlike GMAW (MIG/MAG welding), this welding process is easier to master.",
    "Quick consumable switching from one material type to another.",
    "Welded metal will cool at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation.",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current level, this process represents no risk of lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["It's easy to be mechanized.",
    "Does not require external shielding gas and can be used outdoors in light to moderate winds.",
    "Due to the possibility to weld at any current level, this process represents no risk of lack of fusion.",
    "Welded metal will cool at slower rates as it receives heat from the arc's radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["A high deposition rate.",
    "The process is not very sensitive to air currents, facilitating its use in the field.",
    "The risk of generating slag inclusions in the weld metal is very low.",
    "The Operating Factor is higher compared to other arc welding processes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["A high deposition rate.",
    "The risk of generating slag inclusions in the weld metal is very low.",
    "Can be used in areas/joints with limited access.",
    "The Operating Factor is higher compared to other arc welding processes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SMAW (MMA welding)?",
    answers: ["A high deposition rate.",
    "The risk of generating slag inclusions in the weld metal is very low.",
    "The Operating Factor is higher compared to other arc welding processes.",
    "Welding can be carried out in all positions, in different materials and even in dissimilar materials."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The coating of the covered electrode performs one of the following functions, which one?",
    answers: ["Reduces welding residual stresses.",
    "Protects the weld pool from atmospheric contamination.",
    "Increases the melting rate of the electrode core.",
    "Protects the electrode core against oxidation during storage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The coating of the covered electrode performs one of the following functions, which one?",
    answers: ["Reduces welding residual stresses.",
    "Increases the melting rate of the electrode core.",
    "Produces slag that protects the weld pool, droplets in transfer and shapes the surface geometry of the weld bead.",
    "Protects the electrode core against oxidation during storage."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"After graduating, you think about setting up a welding shop. How would you justify buying a TIG (GTAW) machine instead of a coated electrode welding machine?",
    answers: ["A TIG machine allows welding with covered electrodes when tungsten electrodes are lacking or welding by the TIG process when covered electrodes are lacking.",
    "A TIG machine is normally also used for GMAW (MIG/MAG) and SMAW (MMA) welding processes.",
    "When using a TIG machine to weld with covered electrodes, the weld quality will be much better.",
    "The same machine can be used for both welding thick plates with covered electrodes and for TIG welding of very thin plates (< 1.5 mm)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    }, {
    question:"To increase the mechanical strength of metals, it is sought to restrict the movement of dislocations. One of the basic mechanisms for this is:",
    answers: ["the reduction of metal anisotropy;",
    "the grain size reduction;",
    "hot deformation (causing hardening of the metal);",
    "application of continuous casting which reduces the occurrence of dislocations."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"To increase the mechanical strength of metals, it is sought to restrict the movement of dislocations. One of the basic mechanisms for this is:",
    answers: ["the reduction of metal anisotropy;",
    "a grain size increase;",
    "cold deformation (causing hardening of the metal);",
    "application of continuous casting which reduces the occurrence of dislocations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"To increase the mechanical strength of metals, it is sought to restrict the movement of dislocations. One of the basic mechanisms for this is:",
    answers: ["the reduction of metal anisotropy;",
    "a grain size increase;",
    "hot deformation (causing hardening of the metal);",
    "coherent precipitation (addition of alloying elements)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A dendritic structure can be formed during the following operation:",
    answers: ["Cold working process.",
    "Heat treatment.",
    "Foundry.",
    "Welding with MIG/MAG (131/135) process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the properties of steels with increasing carbon contents.",
    answers: ["Hardness, strength limit and impact resistance increase.",
    "Strength limit, hardness and ductility increase, but impact strength decreases.",
    "Strength limit and hardness increase, but impact resistance decreases.",
    "The hardness decreases, so the deformation capacity increases."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Steels that contain, in addition to carbon, alloying elements such as Cr, Ni, Mn, V, Mo, etc., in total content less than 5% are usually referred to as:",
    answers: ["carbon steel alloys;",
    "low alloy carbon steels;",
    "low alloy steels;",
    "high alloy carbon steels."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the major element in stainless steel?",
    answers: ["Iron.",
    "Nickel.",
    "Molybdenum.",
    "Chromium."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following metals has the lowest density?",
    answers: ["Aluminium.",
    "Steel.",
    "Cast Iron.",
    "Stainless Steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is steel?",
    answers: ["An alloy of iron and 2.5% of carbon.",
    "An alloy of 2.5% of carbon, chromium and iron.",
    "An alloy of carbon and iron with usually less than 2% of carbon.",
    "An alloy of carbon and iron with normally less than 0.1% of carbon"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Stainless steels are:",
    answers: ["Steels with a chromium content between 2% and 5%;",
    "Steels having a chromium content of less than 2%;",
    "Steels with chromium and often nickel.",
    "Steels with more than 10.5% of nickel."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The metal's ability to withstand a force applied against it is called:",
    answers: ["Static resistance of the material.",
    "Dynamic strength of the material.",
    "Mechanical strength of the material.",
    "Cyclic resistance of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The yield strength of a metal is determined by:",
    answers: ["Rockwell test;",
    "Brinell test;",
    "Tensile test;",
    "Charpy test."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which property is NOT determined by a tensile test?",
    answers: ["Fatigue resistance.",
    "Yield strength.",
    "Elongation.",
    "Ductility."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The Charpy impact test measures:",
    answers: ["hardness of material;",
    "hardenability of material;",
    "elastic strength of material;",
    "toughness of material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The melting point range of carbon steel is:",
    answers: ["1150 °C - 1250 °C",
    "1250 °C - 1350 °C",
    "1450 °C - 1550 °C",
    "1550 °C - 1650 °C"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Carbon causes many problems in steels. Why aren't carbonless steels produced?",
    answers: ["Fe-Mn steels, which do not contain carbon, have inferior mechanical properties compared to Fe-C steels.",
    "Fe-Si steels, which do not contain carbon, have inferior mechanical properties compared to Fe-C steels.",
    "Other chemical compounds of iron do not exist, only with carbon.",
    "Steel is the “mixture” of iron (Fe) with exactly carbon (C). Without carbon, there is no steel!"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The point at which permanent deformation takes place during a tensile test is called:",
    answers: ["Permanent deformation tension;",
    "Yield strength;",
    "Rupture starting point;",
    "\"Starting point of a \"\"necking\"\".\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The ultimate stress which a material can withstand without fracture is:",
    answers: ["proportional limit stress;",
    "yield strength;",
    "ultimate strength;",
    "yield upper limit."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The percentage of elongation of a material is determined by subjecting the material to a:",
    answers: ["hardness test;",
    "tensile test;",
    "impact test;",
    "creep test."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What does the hardness test of a material determine?",
    answers: ["The resistance of a material to plastic and elastic deformation in a determined point.",
    "The resistance of the material to impact.",
    "The resistance of a material to indentation.",
    "The ability of a material to resist a sharp blow."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The dividing \"\"carbon\"\" line between steel and cast irons is:\"",
    answers: ["0.10% - 0.20% of carbon;",
    "0.30% - 0.50% of carbon;",
    "1.00% - 1.50% of carbon;",
    "1.70% - 2.10% of carbon."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is true of white cast iron?",
    answers: ["Extremely hard.",
    "Ductile.",
    "Non-magnetic.",
    "Weldable."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The term \"\"corrosion resistance\"\" refers to a materials ability to resist:\"",
    answers: ["abrasion;",
    "chemical attack;",
    "heat;",
    "mechanical forces."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Rust associated with steel is the result of:",
    answers: ["erosion;",
    "corrosion;",
    "precipitation;",
    "segregation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The approximate temperature of coke inside a blast furnace is:",
    answers: ["1000 ºC;",
    "1500 ºC;",
    "2000 ºC;",
    "2500 ºC."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The atmosphere inside a working blast furnace is mainly:",
    answers: ["carbon dioxide, carbon monoxide, and oxygen.",
    "carbon monoxide, nitrogen, and oxygen.",
    "nitrogen, oxygen and sulphur.",
    "oxygen, sulphur dioxide, and carbon dioxide."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which gas is formed when coke is burnt in a blast furnace?",
    answers: ["Oxygen.",
    "Carbon dioxide.",
    "Carbon monoxide.",
    "Natural gas."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Alloy steels, tool steels, or stainless steels are generally produced by which process?",
    answers: ["Bessemer process.",
    "Electric Arc Furnace process.",
    "Blast Furnace process.",
    "Open Hearth Furnace process."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Raw iron produced in a blast furnace:",
    answers: ["is ready to be used for the production of structural steel;",
    "contains too much carbon to be used without further refining;",
    "contains too little sulphur to be used for the production of structural steel;",
    "contains too little carbon to be used for the production of structural steel."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the heat measurement unit?",
    answers: ["Joule.",
    "Degree Celsius.",
    "Degree Fahrenheit.",
    "Kelvin."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which carbon class steel are automotive springs made from?",
    answers: ["Mild steel.",
    "Medium carbon steel.",
    "High carbon steel.",
    "Very high carbon steel."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Medium carbon steel has a carbon content of:",
    answers: ["0.30 to 0.45%.",
    "0.45 to 0.65%.",
    "0.65 to 0.75%.",
    "0.75 to 0.85%."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Low carbon steel has a carbon content of:",
    answers: ["0.05 to 0.30%.",
    "0.30 to 0.45%.",
    "0.45 to 0.65%.",
    "0.65 to 0.75%."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the steel production process:",
    answers: ["Steel is any Iron-Carbon alloy with up to 2.0% of carbon content;",
    "Steel is the main product of the blast furnace of interest to the metalworking industry;",
    "The raw materials for the production of pig iron are: iron ore, coal, slag and air;",
    "In the blast furnace, pig iron is produced and carbon is added to the converter to obtain the desired carbon content of the steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cast iron would be classified as having:",
    answers: ["low carbon content;",
    "medium carbon content;",
    "high carbon content;",
    "very high carbon content."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following properties is true for grey cast iron?",
    answers: ["Low wear resistance.",
    "Low damping capacity.",
    "Very low ductility.",
    "High melting point."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What properties has copper compared to steel?",
    answers: ["Higher thermal expansion",
    "Smaller density.",
    "Higher melting point.",
    "Higher tensile strength."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Oxide of which of the following elements ensures the corrosion resistance of stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Manganese.",
    "Chromium.",
    "Nickel.",
    "Vanadium."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A quick check whether a stainless steel is an austenitic one may be:",
    answers: ["by checking whether it is magnetic or not;",
    "by checking whether its surface is hard;",
    "by looking out for any traces of rust;",
    "by fulfilling the spark testing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The phenomenon of heat transfer within the body of a material is called:",
    answers: ["radiation;",
    "conduction;",
    "convection;",
    "thermal flow."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What cooling speed is used to build up the iron-carbon equilibrium diagram?",
    answers: ["Very low.",
    "Medium.",
    "Variable.",
    "Very high."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Point out the correct statement regarding the crystal structure imperfections called dislocations:",
    answers: ["during plastic deformation the number of dislocations drastically reduces;",
    "the elastic deformation of the material results mainly from the movement of dislocations;",
    "the presence of dislocations worsens the material's mechanical properties (mechanical strength, hardness, ...);",
    "dislocations are crystalline linear defects that, when there are no obstacles for their movement, facilitate the plastic deformation of the crystals."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Point out the correct statement regarding the crystal structure imperfections called dislocations:",
    answers: ["during plastic deformation the number of dislocations drastically reduces;",
    "the elastic deformation of the material results mainly from the movement of dislocations;",
    "the presence of dislocations worsens the material's mechanical properties (mechanical strength, hardness, ...);",
    "the movement of dislocations can stop at the material surface, in the grain boundary or in a precipitate or other defect."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Point out the correct statement regarding the crystal structure imperfections called dislocations:",
    answers: ["during plastic deformation the number of dislocations drastically reduces;",
    "the elastic deformation of the material results mainly from the movement of dislocations;",
    "the presence of dislocations worsens the material's mechanical properties (mechanical strength, hardness, ...);",
    "the plastic deformation of the material results mainly from the movement of dislocations;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Point out the correct statement regarding the crystal structure imperfections called dislocations:",
    answers: ["during plastic deformation the number of dislocations drastically reduces;",
    "the elastic deformation of the material results mainly from the movement of dislocations;",
    "the presence of dislocations worsens the material's mechanical properties (mechanical strength, hardness, ...);",
    "the mechanical strength of material can be increased by restricting the movement of dislocations."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Point out the correct statement regarding the crystal structure imperfections called dislocations:",
    answers: ["during plastic deformation the number of dislocations drastically reduces;",
    "the elastic deformation of the material results mainly from the movement of dislocations;",
    "the presence of dislocations worsens the material's mechanical properties (mechanical strength, hardness, ...);",
    "the presence of dislocations results in lattice distortion, so that certain regions suffer compressive stresses, while others suffer tensile stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Point out the correct statement regarding the crystal structure imperfections called dislocations:",
    answers: ["during plastic deformation the number of dislocations drastically reduces;",
    "the elastic deformation of the material results mainly from the movement of dislocations;",
    "the presence of dislocations worsens the material's mechanical properties (mechanical strength, hardness, ...);",
    "\"when an atom of another element is \"\"in the way\"\", the movement of the dislocation is restricted (increased resistance of the material!).\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Point out the correct statement regarding the crystal structure imperfections called dislocations:",
    answers: ["during plastic deformation the number of dislocations drastically reduces;",
    "the elastic deformation of the material results mainly from the movement of dislocations;",
    "the presence of dislocations worsens the material's mechanical properties (mechanical strength, hardness, ...);",
    "because of dislocations movement difficulties in presence of atoms of different size, solid solutions of metals are always more resistant than their pure constituent metals."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Point out the correct statement regarding the crystal structure imperfections called dislocations:",
    answers: ["during plastic deformation the number of dislocations drastically reduces;",
    "the elastic deformation of the material results mainly from the movement of dislocations;",
    "the presence of dislocations worsens the material's mechanical properties (mechanical strength, hardness, ...);",
    "The presence of interstitial or substitutional alloy elements causes an increase in mechanical strength because they cause a matrix crystalline structure deformation and thus the dislocation movements become more difficult."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What are the three raw materials used to produce iron?",
    answers: ["Coke, limestone and carbon.",
    "Hematite, iron ore and coke. ",
    "Limestone, carbon and iron ore.",
    "Iron ore, coke and limestone."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"In technical drawing, a dashed line of medium thickness ( - - - - - - ) is a:",
    answers: ["centre line;",
    "hidden line; ",
    "visible line; ",
    "dimension line."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In technical drawing, a continuous line of medium thickness is a:",
    answers: ["centre line;",
    "hidden line; ",
    "visible line; ",
    "dimension line."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In technical drawing, a continuous thin line is a:",
    answers: ["centre line;",
    "hidden line; ",
    "visible line; ",
    "dimension line."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In technical drawing, a dash-dot (chain) line is a:",
    answers: ["centre line;",
    "hidden line; ",
    "visible line; ",
    "dimension line."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A stress is:",
    answers: ["a force per unit area;",
    "an area per unit force.",
    "a force per unit volume;",
    "a force per unit displacement."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The steel columns that support a large building should have which type of strength?",
    answers: ["Compressive.",
    "Tensile.",
    "Impact.",
    "Torsional."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About deformation phenomenon, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Temperature variations in a body cause distortions and not deformations;",
    "According to the law of conservation of deformation, the elastic deformation is converted into plastic deformation;",
    "According to the law of conservation of deformation, the plastic deformation is converted into elastic deformation;",
    "When a force is applied to a body, it tends to change its shape and/or its dimension. These changes are called deformations and can be visible or practically imperceptible."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About deformation phenomenon, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Temperature variations in a body cause distortions and not deformations;",
    "According to the law of conservation of deformation, the elastic deformation is converted into plastic deformation;",
    "According to the law of conservation of deformation, the plastic deformation is converted into elastic deformation;",
    "Poisson's ratio states that longitudinal strains are accompanied by transverse strains."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Stresses are classified as normal (acting at a right angle to the surface), shear (the angle is zero) and angular (any other angle);",
    "The stress is measured in KPa/mm2;",
    "The normal stresses caused by the normal force (N) in the cross section of area (A) are calculated by: σ = N/A;",
    "Usually shear stresses are much greater than normal stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Stresses are classified as normal (acting at a right angle to the surface), shear (the angle is zero) and angular (any other angle);",
    "The stress is measured in KPa/mm2;",
    "The average tangential stress caused by the shear force (Q) in the cross section of area (A) is calculated by: σ = Q/A;",
    "Usually shear stresses are much greater than normal stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Stresses are classified as normal (acting at a right angle to the surface), shear (the angle is zero) and angular (any other angle);",
    "The stress is measured in KPa/mm2;",
    "The force per unit area that acts perpendicular to the area is defined as the normal stress;",
    "Tensile stress results in shortening of the solid;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Stresses are classified as normal (acting at a right angle to the surface), shear (the angle is zero) and angular (any other angle);",
    "The stress is measured in KPa/mm2;",
    "The force per unit area that acts tangentially to the area is called the shear stress;",
    "Compressive stress results in elongation of the solid;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Stresses are classified as normal (acting at a right angle to the surface), shear (the angle is zero) and angular (any other angle);",
    "The stress is measured in KPa/mm2;",
    "Normal stress can be tensile or compressive;",
    "Usually shear stresses are much greater than normal stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Compressive stress results in elongation of the solid;",
    "Compressive strength of a solid body is the maximum compressive stress experienced by the body before an elastic deformation is observed;",
    "When a solid body is stretched by applying with two equal forces normal to cross-sectional area, it is known as tensile stress;",
    "Tensile stress results in shortening of the solid;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Tensile stress results in shortening of the solid;",
    "Compressive strength of a solid body is the maximum compressive stress experienced by the body before an elastic deformation is observed;",
    "When a solid body is compressed by an externally applied force, restoring force is developed which originates a compressive stress;",
    "Usually shear stresses are much greater than normal stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Tensile strength is comparatively higher than compressive strength for both ductile and brittle materials;",
    "Compressive strength of a solid body is the maximum compressive stress experienced by the body before an elastic deformation is observed;",
    "If the direction of the force is parallel to the plane of the object. The deformation will be along that plane. The stress experienced by the object here is shear stress;",
    "Compressive stress results in elongation of the solid;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Tensile strength is comparatively higher than compressive strength for both ductile and brittle materials;",
    "Compressive strength of a solid body is the maximum compressive stress experienced by the body before an elastic deformation is observed;",
    "Tensile stress results in elongation of the solid;",
    "Usually shear stresses are much greater than normal stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Tensile strength is comparatively higher than compressive strength for both ductile and brittle materials;",
    "Compressive strength of a solid body is the maximum compressive stress experienced by the body before an elastic deformation is observed;",
    "Compressive stress results in shortening of the solid;",
    "Usually shear stresses are much greater than normal stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Tensile stress results in shortening of the solid;",
    "Compressive strength of a solid body is the maximum compressive stress experienced by the body before an elastic deformation is observed;",
    "Compressive strength is comparatively higher than tensile strength for both ductile and brittle materials;",
    "Compressive stress results in elongation of the solid;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding stresses in a solid body, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Compressive stress results in elongation of the solid;",
    "Compressive strength of a solid body is the maximum compressive stress experienced by the body before an elastic deformation is observed;",
    "The definition for normal stress and shear stress are similar; the difference is in the directions of forces.",
    "Tensile stress results in shortening of the solid;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"For linear elastic stress-strain behaviour:",
    answers: ["Elastic strain is in linear proportion with the applied load;",
    "The deformation is greater if the load is applied cyclically (an increase in load is followed by a restricted reduction in load, which in turn is followed by an increase in load, ...);",
    "The linear-elastic characteristic of the stress-strain diagram has no practical application as it does not take into account the load application rate;",
    "This characteristic refers to an idealized material. A real material will always have some residual deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"For linear elastic stress-strain behaviour:",
    answers: ["No deformation remains when the load is not any more applied;",
    "The deformation is greater if the load is applied cyclically (an increase in load is followed by a restricted reduction in load, which in turn is followed by an increase in load, ...);",
    "The linear-elastic characteristic of the stress-strain diagram has no practical application as it does not take into account the load application rate;",
    "This characteristic refers to an idealized material. A real material will always have some residual deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"For linear elastic stress-strain behaviour:",
    answers: ["Young modulus is represented by the ratio between stress and strain;",
    "The deformation is greater if the load is applied cyclically (an increase in load is followed by a restricted reduction in load, which in turn is followed by an increase in load, ...);",
    "The linear-elastic characteristic of the stress-strain diagram has no practical application as it does not take into account the load application rate;",
    "This characteristic refers to an idealized material. A real material will always have some residual deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A distortion is called permanent when it is caused by:",
    answers: ["elastic deformation;",
    "plastic deformation;",
    "longitudinal deformation;",
    "transverse deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"A welder performed a one-meter weld in 200 s. What is the welding speed in cm/min?",
    answers: ["30 cm/min.",
    "60 cm/min.",
    "0,5 cm/min.",
    "50 cm/min."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"When a metal is evenly heated and allowed to expand freely, after being cooled down:",
    answers: ["it will not return to its original shape.",
    "it will do return to its original shape.",
    "it will become a little bit bigger.",
    "it will become distorted."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"When a metal is heated and restrained in one direction and then cooled down, it will:",
    answers: ["become shorter in this direction.",
    "become longer in this direction.",
    "return to its original shape.",
    "not suffer any shape alterations (due to the imposed restraint)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What direction does metal expand when preheated without being restrained?",
    answers: ["It depends on direction of the heat application.",
    "Transversely (across its width).",
    "longitudinally (lengthwise).",
    "Volumetrically (in all directions)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following does NOT burn? ",
    answers: ["Magnesium.",
    "Sugar.",
    "Oxygen.",
    "Sodium."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the major risk associated with dropping a container of covered electrodes?",
    answers: ["It may hurt your feet.",
    "You could damage the floor. ",
    "You may damage the packing.",
    "The electrode coating might break off."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What does a welding helmet NOT provide protection from?",
    answers: ["Gamma rays.",
    "Infrared rays.",
    "Spatter.",
    "Sparks."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the measurement of arc welding electrical parameters, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The welding current shall be measured as close to the arc as possible;",
    "The arc voltage can be measured at any point in the circuit of an arc welding process, as its value is independent of the measurement position;",
    "To determine the arc electrical power, the current and voltage are measured at the same point of the welding circuit;",
    "The current can be measured at any point of the arc welding circuit, as its value is independent of the measurement point."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the measurement of arc welding electrical parameters, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The welding current shall be measured as close to the arc as possible;",
    "The arc voltage can be measured at any point in the circuit of an arc welding process, as its value is independent of the measurement position;",
    "To determine the arc electrical power, the current and voltage are measured at the same point of the welding circuit;",
    "Arc voltage shall be measured as close to the arc as possible."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the measurement of arc welding electrical parameters, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The welding current shall be measured as close to the arc as possible;",
    "The arc voltage can be measured at any point in the circuit of an arc welding process, as its value is independent of the measurement position;",
    "To determine the arc electrical power, the current and voltage are measured at the same point of the welding circuit;",
    "To measure arc voltage in SAW welding, the voltmeter should be connected between the torch and the workpiece."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the measurement of arc welding electrical parameters, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The welding current shall be measured as close to the arc as possible;",
    "The arc voltage can be measured at any point in the circuit of an arc welding process, as its value is independent of the measurement position;",
    "To determine the arc electrical power, the current and voltage are measured at the same point of the welding circuit;",
    "To measure arc voltage in MIG/MAG welding, the voltmeter should be connected between the wire feeder and the workpiece."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which one of the following items is an example of a fuel (for a fire)?",
    answers: ["Oxygen.",
    "Electricity.",
    "Wood.",
    "Air."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the International System of Units, speed is measured in:",
    answers: ["m/min;",
    "m/s;",
    "km/h;",
    "mm/min."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the International System of Units, density (specific mass) is measured in:",
    answers: ["Pa/m3 (pascal per cubic metre);",
    "kg/m3 (kilogram per cubic metre);",
    "g/l (gram per litre);",
    "N/m3 (newton per cubic metre)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the International System of Units, mass is measured in:",
    answers: ["kg (kilogram);",
    "N (newton);",
    "gm (gram mass);",
    "kgm (kilogram-mass)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the International System of Units, the moment of a force (torque) is measured in:",
    answers: ["N m (newton metre);",
    "kg M (kilogram metre);",
    "G m (gram metre);",
    "Pa (pascal)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the International System of Units, power is measured in:",
    answers: ["W (watt);",
    "J (joule);",
    "H (Horse);",
    "W-h (watt hour)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the International System of Units, energy (amount of heat) is measured in:",
    answers: ["W (watt);",
    "Cal (calorie);",
    "H (Horse);",
    "J (joule)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the International System of Units, temperature is measured in:",
    answers: ["degree Celsius (°C) or kelvin (K) ou degree Fahrenheit (°F);",
    "degree Fahrenheit (°F) or degree Celsius (°C);",
    "degree Celsius (°C) or kelvin (K);",
    "degree Fahrenheit (°F) or kelvin (K)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the International System of Units, pressure is measured in:",
    answers: ["N/m3 (newton per cubic metre);",
    "N/mm3 (newton per cubic millimetre);",
    "kg/m2 (kilogram per square metre);",
    "N/m2 (newton per square metre = Pa - pascal)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the units is written according to the International System of Units?",
    answers: ["KW;",
    "kA;",
    "mPa;",
    "KPa."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    }]
    
    
;